marlboro.com 2010-12-27

# Marlboro.com - Official Website for Marlboro Cigarettes

Last updated: September 2009.

We at Philip Morris USA respect your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you. This Privacy Statement describes the types of personal information collected by Philip Morris USA for its brands online. This statement does not apply to Philip Morris USA websites that do not display or link to this statement, or that have their own privacy statement.

Our Privacy Statement also describes how we may use the information that we collect, to whom and under what circumstances we may disclose it, and the measures we take to protect the security of the information. We also tell you how you can contact us, remove your name from our brand contact list (which is used to send communications to you), or answer any questions you may have about our privacy approach. By joining our brand contact list, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement. 

Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

  * Information We Collect
  * Information We Use
  * Cookies and Flash Cookies
  * Web Beacons 
  *   * Links to Third-Party Websites
  * How We Protect Personal Information
  * Controlling "Spam" or Unsolicited Email
  * Your Choices
  * Updates to Our Privacy Statement
  * How to Contact Us

### Information We Collect

Our Contact List: When you request to be added to our brand contact list, we may ask you to provide personal information, such as your name, address, date of birth, email address and telephone number. We also may work with third parties to supplement the information you provide with other data so that we may customize our offers to you.

Age and Identity Verification: If you elect to sign up to our brand contact list, for age and identity verification purposes, we may collect, and work with third parties to confirm your age and identity by using, your name, address, date of birth, the last four digits of your Social Security number and in some cases your full Social Security number.

Non-Personal Aggregate Data: In addition, we may collect certain non-personal, aggregate information when you visit a Philip Morris USA marketing website. This information tells us such things as how many users visited those websites and which pages were accessed. Additionally, when you visit our websites, your browser may send us certain standard information that it sends to websites you visit, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and language, access times and referring website addresses.

return to top

### Information We Use

We may use your personal information for any of the following purposes: (1) to provide you content, offers and advertising by direct mail, email and/or in other ways; (2) to monitor and conduct reviews of our products and offers; (3) to help us improve and develop products; (4) to send you administrative and/or legislative-related communications; and (5) to otherwise contact you related to any of these reasons or at your request. 

return to top

### Cookies and Flash Cookies

Like many companies, we use cookies on many of our websites. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain websites. Cookies may enhance and personalize your online experience by helping you find the information you want. 

For example, we may use cookies to tell us whether you've visited us before or if you're a new visitor, to enable you to use certain website features and to monitor and maintain information about your use of our websites. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie and how to delete existing cookies.

We also use technology called Flash Local Shared Objects (also known as "flash cookies"). These are data files that allow us to personalize and tailor our websites so that we may enhance your web-browsing experience. A flash cookie is exactly like the browser cookie mentioned above, plus it has the capacity to store more complex data. A flash cookie can only be read by the website domain that created the cookie in the first place. A flash cookie cannot access or remember your email address or other personal information (and we would not retain that information unless you provide us with it through the other means described in this Privacy Statement). By controlling your security settings you can control the way flash cookies work, how much data is stored and maintain a level of privacy with which you're comfortable. You can also disable flash cookies by changing your Flash Player settings. For more information on how to manage your local content settings, click here.

return to top

### Web Beacons

Certain pages on our websites also contain web beacons (also known as spotlight tags, Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs), which are tiny graphic images that may appear on our websites and in our emails. Web beacons help us analyze our customers' online behavior and measure the effectiveness of our websites and email communications. We work with certain service providers that help us track, collect and analyze this information. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having your information used by our service providers, click here.

Web beacons on our websites may be used to collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the features you use, the links you click and other actions you take in connection with the websites. This information may include your computer's IP address, your browser type, your Internet service provider (ISP), your operating system, date and time information and other technical information about your computer. Web beacons in our emails may be used to track your interactions with those messages, such as when you receive, open, forward or click a link in an email message from us.

We may also combine the information we collect from cookies and web beacons with other information that we have collected from you. This information may be used for purposes of improving our websites, personalizing your online experience, tailoring our communications with you and determining the effectiveness of our advertising.

return to top

We may share your personal information with Philip Morris USA's affiliates, including ones that market tobacco products like U.S. Smokeless Tobacco Company and John Middleton. Philip Morris USA, U.S. Smokeless Tobacco Company and John Middleton are subsidiaries of Altria Group, Inc. To learn more about Altria Group, Inc. and its companies visit http://www.altria.com/en/cms/About_Altria/At_A_Glance/default.aspx

We may share personal information with third-party service providers who we have retained to perform services on our behalf. These service providers are contractually restricted from using or disclosing the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. 

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided through our websites in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

return to top

### Links to Third-Party Websites

From time to time, we may provide links to third-party websites. These websites operate independently from Philip Morris USA, and may have their own privacy statements in place, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are unrelated to Philip Morris USA, we are not responsible for their content or any use of the websites.

return to top

### How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards on this website to help protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration or destruction of the personal information you provide on the PM USA brand marketing sites. We use secure socket layer (SSL) technology to help keep the personal information you provide secure.

In addition to these safeguards, to the extent your Social Security number (SSN) is collected for verification purposes, we also take measures to maintain its confidentiality, to protect it from unlawful disclosure, and limit access to it by unauthorized third parties. We will not make your SSN available to the general public, will not print your SSN on any card required to access products or services, will not require you to transmit your SSN on the Internet unless the connection is secure or the SSN is encrypted, nor will we require you to transmit your SSN to access a website without requiring additional authentication.

return to top

### Controlling "Spam" or Unsolicited Email

Philip Morris USA is concerned about controlling unsolicited commercial email, or "spam." We are against the use of spam and will not sell, lease or rent our email lists to third parties.

return to top

### Your Choices

If you would like your name removed from our brand contact list, please call 1-800-558-8666.

return to top

### Updates to Our Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices. If there are material changes to our Privacy Statement, we will post a prominent notice on our websites and indicate at the top of the statement when it was most recently updated, and/or provide other appropriate notice to you.

return to top

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, or if you would like us to update information we have about you, please contact us by calling us at 1-888-977-2246.

return to top
